Guide to the Pennsylvania Environmental Council Collection, 1970-1998 AIS.1999.18
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Environmental Concerns, 1971-1999; I.
  - Waste-Solid Management Facility Financing, 1985, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Waste-Solid Management Facility Permitting, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Waste-Solid Management Facility Siting, 1984-1985, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Waste-Solid Management Facility Siting, Lawrence County Ordinance, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Waste-Solid Management Landfills, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Waste-Solid Management Landfills, 1987-1991 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Waste-Solid Management Landfills, Photographs, undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Waste-Solid Management, ORFA, 1987-1988 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Waste-Solid Management Packaging, 1981, 1990-1992 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Waste-Solid Management Pennsylvania, 1987-1991 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Waste-Solid Management Pennsylvania, undated (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Waste-Solid Management Philadelphia, 1987-1991 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Waste-Solid Management Philadelphia, 1987-1988 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Waste-Solid Management Philadelphia, Trash to Stream, 1987-1988 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Waste-Solid Management, RCRA Reauthorization, 1991-1992 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Waste-Solid Management Recycling, 1989-1992 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Waste-Solid Management Recycling, 1986-1991 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Waste-Solid Management Recycling, 1985-1990 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Waste-Solid Management Recycling Aluminum, 1986-1993 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Waste-Solid Management Recycling Appliances, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Waste-Solid Management Recycling Aseptic Drink Boxes, 1991-1992 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Waste-Solid Management Recycling at Work, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Waste-Solid Management Recycling in Apartments/Condos, 1990-1992 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Waste-Solid Management Recycling Batteries, 1988, 1992-1993 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Waste-Solid Management Recycling Christmas Trees, undated (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Waste-Solid Management Recycling Glass, 1987-1991 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Waste-Solid Management Recycling in Institutions, 1990-1992 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Waste-Solid Management Recycling Legislation, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Waste-Solid Management Recycling Metals, 1990-1991 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Waste-Solid Management Recycling Newspaper Clippings, 1987-1996 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Waste-Solid Management Recycling Paper, 1989-1991 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Waste-Solid Management Recycling Plastic, 1990-1995 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Waste-Solid Management Recycling Plastic, 1986-1990 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Waste-Solid Management Recycling Plastic, 1985-1990 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Waste-Solid Management Recycling Polystyrene, 1989-1990 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Waste-Solid Management Recycling Polystyrene, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Waste-Solid Management Recycling Polystyrene, 1989-1990 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Waste-Solid Management Recycling Textiles, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Waste-Solid Management Recycling Tires, 1986, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Waste-Solid Management Recycling Tires, 1989-1992 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Waste-Solid Management Recycling Working Programs, 1984, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Waste-Solid Management Recycling Working Programs, 1986, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Waste-Solid Recycling Market Development, 1991-1993 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Waste-Solid Management Reduction, 1987-1988 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Water, 1988-1998 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Water-Drinking, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Water-Drinking, 1985-1991 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Water-Drinking, 1977-1988 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Water-Drinking, 1985, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Water-Drinking Legislation, Safe Drinking Water Act, 1984-1986, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Water-Drinking Proposed Legislation, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Water-Drought, 1984, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Water-Ground, 1988-1993 (Box 1, Folder 317)
  - Water-Ground, 1980-1987 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Water-Ground, 1988-1992 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Water-Ground, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Water-Ground, 1986-1988 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Water-Ground, 1985-1989 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Water-Ground, 1985-1990 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Water-Ground, Cleanup Alternatives, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Water-Ground, Effects on Coal Mining, 1982-1993 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Water-Ground, Office of Ground Water Protection, 1984, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Water-Ground, Southeast Pennsylvania, 1981, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Water-Ground, Southwest Pennsylvania, 1977. 1985 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Water-Ground, Southwest Pennsylvania, 1973, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Water-Mon Oil Spill, 1988, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Water-Ocean Dumping, 1986-1991 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Water-Pamphlets, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Water-Residual Graywater, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Water-Schuylkill River Wild and Scenic Rivers Study, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Water-Surface, Chesapeake Bay, 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Water-Surface, Chesapeake Bay, 1986,1988 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Water-Surface, Chesapeake Bay, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Water-Surface, Chesapeake Bay, 1988-1991 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Water-Surface, Chlorine, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Water-Surface, Coastal Land Management, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Water-Surface, Coastal Zone Management, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Water-Surface, Coastal Zone Management Act, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Water-Surface, Delaware Estuary, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Water-Surface, Delaware River, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Water-Surface, F.E. Walter Reservoir, 1986, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Water-Surface, Great Lakes, 1986-1987 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Water-Surface, Nutrient Loading, 1988-1993 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Water-Surface, Pennsylvania Pumps, undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Water-Surface, Pennsylvania Rivers, 1984, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Water-Surface, Phosphate Ban, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Water-Surface, Phosphate Detergent Effect on Pennsylvania Water, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Water-Surface, Rivers, 1983, 1984, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Water-Surface, Rivers/Lakes, 1977, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Water-Surface, Scenic Rivers Program, 1989-1991 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Water-Surface, Scenic Rivers Program, 1979, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Water-Surface, Stormwater, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Water-Surface, Stormwater Regulations, 1991-1992 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Water-Surface, Usage/Management, undated (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Water-Surface, Wastewater, 1982-1988 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Water-Surface, Well Head Protection, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Wetlands, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Wetlands-Destruction/Lawsuits, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Wetlands-Destruction/Lawsuits, 1986-1991 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Wetlands-Federal Policy, 1988-1991 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Wetlands-Meeting Group, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Wetlands-Mitigation, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Wetlands-Mr. Schmidt and Blue Route, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Wetlands-Ordinances and Legislation, 1987-1988 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Wetlands-Ordinances and Legislation, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Wetlands-Regulations, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Wetlands-Regulations, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Wetlands-State/Regional Policy, 1988-1990 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Wetlands-State/Regional Policy, 1989, 1990, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Wetlands-State/Regional Policy, 1986-1990 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Wetlands-State/Regional Policy, 1987-1991 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Wetlands-State/Regional Policy, 1985, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Wetlands-Water Obstruction Permit, 1986-1990 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Wildlife, undated (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Wildlife, undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Wildlife, 1986-1988 (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Workshops, 1988-1992; II.
  The Pennsylvania Environmental Council (PEC) is an active organization. Not only do they lobby for legislation in the Pennsylvania legislature, but they reach out to the public in informative sessions about environmental topics. The goals of these sessions are to gain support for the environmental legislation, and to educate the public on numerous environmental issues. Some of the sessions are administered by the PEC while other sessions are attended by PEC members. A majority of these sessions were held in cooperation with the Institute for Cooperation in Environmental Management (ICEM). This series is arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Acid Rain, October 27, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Air-Reading Materials, September 21, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Air Quality, 1989-1990 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Air Quality Forum Planning Committee, December 5, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Air Quality Forum, 1990-1991 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Air Quality Forum, December 5, 1990, January 23, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Air Quality Forum, January 1, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Air Quality Forum, February 15, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Air Quality, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Air Quality, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Air Quality Forum, March 22, 1991, May 21, 1991, June 28, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Air Quality, May 12, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Air Quality, May 26, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Air Quality, June 10, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Air Quality, June 6, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Air Quality, September 9, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Air Quality Initiative Resource Information, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Air Quality Initiative Resource Information, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Air Quality Initiative Notes by PEC, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Air Quality, September 9, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Air Quality Miscellaneous, undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Coal Mining, 1996-1997 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Mid-Atlantic Air Quality Iniative, 1990-1991 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
- Meetings/Conferences, 1987-1996; III.
  The Pennsylvania Environmental Council (PEC) convenes several meetings or conferences each year to discuss issues pertinent to their organization. During these semi-annual or annual meetings, the organization discusses their objectives for the year. These objectives include, but are not limited to, dinners, educational activities, media, computers, conferences, task forces and proposed programs. The board members are also responsible for discussing minutes and financials at these events. This series is arranged chronologically.
  - Annual Budget, July 1, 1987-June 30, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Materials, 1986-1987 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - 16th Annual Conference, March 23, 1987 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Not in My Back Yard Slide Show, January 25, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Board Meeting Miscellaneous, March 24, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Board Meeting Originals, March 24, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - 17th Annual Conference Registration/Registration Forms, April 22/22, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - 17th Annual Conference Handout, April, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - 17th Annual Conference Originals, April 21/22, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - 17th Annual Conference Miscellaneous Correspondence, April 1988 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Board Meeting Miscellaneous, July 15, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Board Meeting Originals, July 15, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Board Meeting Miscellaneous, September 9, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Board Meeting Originals, September 15, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - 19th Annual Meeting Registration Forms, October 27, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - 19th Annual Meeting Hawk Mountain, October 27, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Board Member Questionnaire including Responses, November 1988 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Board Meeting Miscellaneous, December 5, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Board Meeting Originals, December 5, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Notes, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Residual Water Regulations, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Residual Water Regulations, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Industrial Site Reuse Seminars, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Historic Preservation, April 23-26, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Environmental Partnership Awards, October 1995 (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - 26th Annual Meeting, December 1995 (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - Annual Meeting, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - Eastern Pennsylvania Abandoned Mill Land and Acid Mine Drainage Conference, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - Environmental History, April 1996 (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 14, Folder 35)
- Legislation, 1971-1999; IV.
  The Pennsylvania Environmental Council (PEC) became a lobbying organization early in its existence. With the help of lawyers like Robert Sugarman, PEC was able to pressure Congress and the Pennsylvania legislature for legislation on environmental issues. A large percentage of the legislation PEC concerned themselves with parallels the environmental issues the organization most adamantly spoke about, such as clean air, clean water, issues with waste, pesticides and chemicals. In addition to lobbying efforts in Congress, the organization also produced "Legislative Updates" to keep the public informed on the status of important bills in both the House and the Senate. This series is arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Act 101 Developments, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 36)
  - Act 101 Developments, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 37)
  - Act 101-PEC Position, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 38)
  - Act 101 Positions, 1988-1990 (Box 14, Folder 39)
  - Acid Rain, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 40)
  - American Heritage Trust Fund, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Bush National Environmental Policy, 1988-1989 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Chemicals, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Clean Air Act, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Clean Air Act, 1989-1990 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Clean Air Act, 1977-1985 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Clean Air Act, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Clean Air Act, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Clean Air Act-Acid Rain Bill, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Clean Air Act Committee PEC, 1991-1992 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Clean Air Act Committee PEC, 1991-1992 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Clean Air Act in Congress, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Clean Air Act in Congress, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Clean Air Act Correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Clean Air Act Residents Amendments Proposal, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Clean Air Legislation Pennsylvania, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Clean Water, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Clean Water Act, 1978-1983 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Communication-Senate Bill 429, 1991-1992 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Committee Agenda, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Conservation Easements, 1989-1990 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - DER, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Department of Energy, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Department of Natural Resources, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - EHB Developments, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Environmental, 1991-1992 (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Environmental, Pending, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Environmental, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Environmental, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Environmental, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Environmental Education, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Environmental Education, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Environmental Violations/Crimes, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Environmental Violations/Crimes, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - EHB-PEC Positions/Correspondence, 1986-1989 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - EHB Positions, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - EPA, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Farm Bill, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Farmland Preservation, 1988 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Farmland Preservation, 1987-1988 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Federal Billboard, 1986 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - GPUAC, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - GPUAC, 1990-1993 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - GPUAC, 1990-1993 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - GPUAC Board, 1994-1995 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - GPUAC Board, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - GPUAC Board, 1993-1994 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - GPUAC Board, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - GPUAC Citizens Assembly Economic Development, 1992-1993 (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - GPUAC Committee, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - GPUAC Neighborhood Development Committee, 1993-1994 (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - GPUAC Urban Affairs, 1990-1992 (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - GPUAC Urban Partnership, 1991-1992 (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - GPUAC Urban Partnership, 1991-1993 (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - Global Warming, 1989-1990 (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - Global Warming Prevention Act, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 28)
  - Governor's Energy Council, 1986 (Box 16, Folder 29)
  - Governor's Moratorium, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 30)
  - Ground Water and Coal Mining, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 31)
  - Ground Water Protection, 1987-1988 (Box 16, Folder 32)
  - Ground Water Protection Strategy, 1988-1990 (Box 16, Folder 33)
  - Ground Water Protection Strategy, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 34)
  - GROW, 1988 (Box 16, Folder 35)
  - Hazardous Waste Cleanup-Congress, 1987 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Hazardous Waste-League of Women Voters Letter, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - IRRC, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - IRRC Seminar, 1987 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Junk Packaging, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Land Bank, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Landfill Proposal, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Landfill Proposal, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Low Level Radioactive Waste, 1987-1988 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous, 1987-1988 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Municipal Ash Policy, 1987 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Municipal Waste Planning, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - National Energy Act, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - National Plumbing Products Efficiency Act, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Negotiated Rulemaking, 1991-1992 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Negotiated Rulemaking, 1991-1992 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Notes-Dave Heiss, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Nutrient Management, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Nutrient Management, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Nutrient Management, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Ozone, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Pennsylvania Bottle Bill, 1985-1986 (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Pennsylvania Bottle Bill, 1985-1990 (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Pennsylvania Bottle Bill, Effects, 1984-1985 (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - PennVest, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Pesticides, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - Pesticides, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 27)
  - Pesticides/Lawn Care, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 28)
  - Pesticides/Lawn Care, 1987-1988 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Pesticides/Lawn Care, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Pesticides Regulation, 1988-1989 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Phosphate Ban, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Phosphate Ban, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Project 88, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Public Access Policy, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Residual Waste, 1971, 1985 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Resource Conservation Recovery Act, 1985 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Resource Conservation Recovery Act, 1984-1986 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Resource Conservation Recovery Act, 1976, 1984 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Right to Know, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Sign Controls, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Solid Waste Management Act, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Superfund(CERCLA), 1984, 1987 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Superfund(CERCLA), 1980, 1987 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Superfund Bills/Summary, 1987-1988 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Superfund Developments, 1987-1988 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Superfund PEC Positions/Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Superfund Penn PIC Letter, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Superfund Positions, 1987-1989 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Superfund Sites, undated (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Superfund Summaries, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act, 1985, 1992-1993 (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Update, 1971-1973 (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - Update Volume 1, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Update Volume 2, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - Update Volume 2 and 3, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - Update Volume 4, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 29)
  - Update Volume 5, 1980 (Box 18, Folder 30)
  - Update Volume 6, 1981 (Box 18, Folder 31)
  - Update Volume 7, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 32)
  - Update Volume 8, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 33)
  - Update Volume 9, 1984 (Box 18, Folder 34)
  - Update Volume 10, 1985-1986 (Box 18, Folder 35)
  - Update, 1987-1989 (Box 18, Folder 36)
  - Update, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 37)
  - Update, 1991-1992 (Box 18, Folder 38)
  - Update, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 39)
  - Update, 1994-1999 (Box 18, Folder 40)
  - VOC Regulations, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 41)
  - VOC Regulation Report, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 42)
  - Wetlands, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 43)
  - Wetlands, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Wetlands Correspondence, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Wetlands Pennsylvania Correspondence, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Wetlands Regulation, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 4)
- Environmental Activities/Projects, 1970-1992; V.
  The Pennsylvania Environmental Council (PEC) has effectively reached out to the public through educational events and policy. Particularly in the early 1990s, PEC held Earthday and Earthweek events emphasizing the importance of the environment. The organization was able to assemble large crowds and conduct small workshops and educational events at this larger gathering. This series is arranged alphabetically by subject.
  On a more policy related note, PEC has used their environmental emphasis to put into effect certain programs. An example of one of these policies or programs is the Green Resources Initiative by PEC. PEC hoped to bring an environmental project (Green Resources) into Pennsylvania communities. "Its purpose is to identify open space and environmental resources throughout Pennsylvania and to stimulate their protection and enhancement through a hands-on, community participation and mapping process" (Green Resources Initiative).
  - Earthfest, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Earthweek Articles/Background, 1970, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Earthweek, Campus Audit Conference, 1989, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Earthweek Coalition, Delaware Valley, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Earthweek Education Packet, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Earthweek Earthfest, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Earthweek Fundraising, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Eartweek Green Pledge, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Earthweek Events Information, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Earthweek Merchandise, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Earthweek National Organization, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Earthweek Newsletter, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Earthweek Public Relations/Marketing, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Earthweek WHYY, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Earthweek Valdez Principles, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Earthweek Workplace Audit, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Earthweek, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Earthweek, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Earthweek, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Earthweek, Earth Sunday, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Earthweek, Earth Sunday Origins, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Earthweek Meeting Logistics, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - Earthweek Thank You's, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - Earthweek Things to Do, undated (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - Earthweek Brochures, undated (Box 19, Folder 29)
  - Earthweek Poster[oversized], 1992 (Map-case 9, Drawer 3)
  - Earth Sunday Poster[oversized], 1993 (Map-case 9, Drawer 3)
  - Green Resources Articles, 1991 (Map-case 9, Folder 30)
  - Green Resources Chester County Data, 1990-1991 (Map-case 9, Folder 31)
  - Green Resources Chester County Open Space Contacts, 1991 (Map-case 9, Folder 32)
  - Green Resources Data/Compiled Logistics, 1992 (Map-case 9, Folder 33)
  - Green Resources First Meeting (Map-case 9, Folder 34)
  - Green Resources London Grove Township, 1992 (Map-case 9, Folder 35)
  - Green Resources Maps, undated (Map-case 9, Folder 36)
  - Green Resources Newspaper Coverage, 1991 (Map-case 9, Folder 37)
  - Green Resources Notes, 1992 (Map-case 9, Folder 38)
  - Green Resources Initiative Proposal, 1990 (Map-case 9, Folder 39)
  - Green Resources Pennsylvania Biodiversity Reserves System, 1991 (Map-case 9, Folder 40)
  - Green Resources Surveys/Letters, 1992 (Map-case 9, Folder 41)